[
   {
      "basics":{
         "easy":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax for adding the header file in the C++ program?",
                  "answers":[
                     "#include<userdefined>",
                     "#include 'userdefined.h'",
                     "<include> 'userdefined.h'",
                     "Both A and B"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Both A and B"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the message in C++ language?",
                  "answers":[
                     "cout <<'Hello world!'",
                     "Cout << Hello world!",
                     "Out <<'Hello world!",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"cout <<'Hello world!'"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
                  "answers":[
                     "$var_name",
                     "VAR_123",
                     "varname@",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"VAR_123"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the address operator?",
                  "answers":[
                     "@",
                     "#",
                     "&",
                     "%"
                  ],
                  "answer":"&"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following features must be supported by any programming language to become a pure object-oriented programming language?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Encapsulation",
                     "Inheritance",
                     "Polymorphism",
                     "All of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"All of the above"
               },
               {
                  "question":"The programming language that has the ability to create new data types is called___.",
                  "answers":[
                     "Overloaded",
                     "Encapsulated",
                     "Reprehensible",
                     "Extensible"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Extensible"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
                  "answers":[
                     "//Comment",
                     "/Comment/",
                     "Comment//",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"//Comment"
               },
               {
                  "question":"C++ is a ___ type of language.",
                  "answers":[
                     "High-level Language",
                     "Low-level language",
                     "Middle-level language",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Middle-level language"
               },
               {
                  "question":"For inserting a new line in C++ program, which one of the following statements can be used?",
                  "answers":[
                     "\n",
                     "\r",
                     "\\a",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"\n"
               },
               {
                  "question":"If we stored five elements or data items in an array, what will be the index address or the index number of the array's last data item?",
                  "answers":[
                     "3",
                     "5",
                     "4",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"4"
               }
            ]
         },
         "medium":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following functions below can be used Allocate space for array in memory?",
                  "answers":[
                     "calloc()",
                     "malloc()",
                     "realloc()",
                     "Both A and B"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Both A and B"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Use of virtual functions implies:",
                  "answers":[
                     "overloading",
                     "overriding",
                     "static binding",
                     "dynamic binding"
                  ],
                  "answer":"dynamic binding"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Declaration a pointer more than once may cause ____.",
                  "answers":[
                     "Error",
                     "Abort",
                     "Trap",
                     "NULL"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Trap"
               },
               {
                  "question":"You can read input that consists of multiple lines of text using:",
                  "answers":[
                     "the normal cout << combination",
                     "the cin.get( ) function with one argument",
                     "the cin.get( ) function with two arguments",
                     "the cin.get( ) function with three arguments"
                  ],
                  "answer":"the cin.get( ) function with two arguments"
               },
               {
                  "question":"The keyword friend does not appear in:",
                  "answers":[
                     "the class allowing access to another class",
                     "the class desiring access to another class",
                     "the private section of a class",
                     "the public section of a class"
                  ],
                  "answer":"the private section of a class"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the formal parameters in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Parameters with which functions are called",
                     "Parameters which are used in the definition of the function",
                     "Variables other than passed parameters in a function",
                     "Variables that are never used in the function"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Parameters with which functions are called"
               },
               {
                  "question":"An exception is caused by:",
                  "answers":[
                     "a runtime error",
                     "a syntax error",
                     "a problem in the operating system",
                     "a hardware problem"
                  ],
                  "answer":"a runtime error"
               }
            ]
         },
         "hard":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"If a member needs to have a unique value for all the objects of that same class, declare the member as",
                  "answers":[
                     "Global variable outside class",
                     "Local variable inside constructor",
                     "Static variable inside a class",
                     "Dynamic variable inside a class"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Static variable inside a class"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which one is not a correct variable type in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "float",
                     "real",
                     "int",
                     "double"
                  ],
                  "answer":"real"
               },
               {
                  "question":"If you wanted to sort many large objects or structures, it would be most efficient to",
                  "answers":[
                     "place them in an array & sort the array",
                     "place pointers to them in an array & sort the array",
                     "place them in a linked list and sort the linked list",
                     "place references to them in an array and sorts the array"
                  ],
                  "answer":"place them in a linked list and sort the linked list"
               },
               {
                  "question":"A class defined within another class is",
                  "answers":[
                     "Nested class",
                     "Inheritance",
                     "Containership",
                     "Encapsulation"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Nested class"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Under which of the following circumstances does synchronization take place?",
                  "answers":[
                     "When the file is closed",
                     "When the buffer is empty",
                     "Explicitly, with manipulators",
                     "both a and c"
                  ],
                  "answer":"When the buffer is empty"
               },
               {
                  "question":"A function call mechanism that passes arguments to a function by passing a copy of the values of the arguments is",
                  "answers":[
                     "call by name",
                     "call by value",
                     "call by reference",
                     "call by value result"
                  ],
                  "answer":"call by value"
               },
               {
                  "question":"In a C language ‘3’ represents",
                  "answers":[
                     "A digit",
                     "An integer",
                     "A character",
                     "A word"
                  ],
                  "answer":"A character"
               }
            ]
         }
      },
      "structs&funcs":{
         "easy":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Where does the execution of the program start?",
                  "answers":[
                     "user-defined function",
                     "main function",
                     "void function",
                     "else function"
                  ],
                  "answer":"main function"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What are mandatory parts of a function declaration?",
                  "answers":[
                     "return type, function name",
                     "return type, function name, parameters",
                     "parameters, function name",
                     "parameters, variables"
                  ],
                  "answer":"return type, function name"
               },
               {
                  "question": "which of the following is used to terminate the function declaration?",
                  "answers":[
                     ";",
                     ")",
                     "]",
                     ":"
                  ],
                  "answer":";"
               },
               {
                  "question":"In a c99 compiler, what is the maximum number of parameters that can be passed to a function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "99",
                     "90",
                     "127",
                     "102"
                  ],
                  "answer":"127"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which is more effective while calling the functions?",
                  "answers":[
                     "call by value",
                     "call by reference",
                     "call by pointer",
                     "call by object"
                  ],
                  "answer":"call by reference"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the scope of a variable declared in a user defined function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "whole program",
                     "only inside the {} block",
                     "the main function",
                     "header section"
                  ],
                  "answer":"only inside the {} block"
               },
               {
                  "question":"In a C++ program, what is the minimum number of functions allowed?",
                  "answers":[
                     "0",
                     "1",
                     "2",
                     "3"
                  ],
                  "answer": "1"
                }
            ]
         },
         "medium":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"The data elements in the structure are also known as",
                  "answers":[
                     "objects",
                     "members",
                     "data",
                     "objects & data"
                  ],
                  "answer":"members"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is used when terminating a structure?",
                  "answers":[
                     ":",
                     "]",
                     ")",
                     ";"
                  ],
                  "answer":";"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What happens when a structure is declared?",
                  "answers":[
                     "it will not allocate any memory",
                     "it will allocate the memory",
                     "it will be declared and initialized",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"it will not allocate any memory"
               },
               {
                  "question":"The declaration of the structure is also called as",
                  "answers":[
                     "structure creator",
                     "structure signifier",
                     "structure specifier",
                     "structure creator & specifier"
                  ],
                  "answer":"structure specifier"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is a properly defined structure?",
                  "answers":[
                     "struct {int a;}",
                     "struct a_struct {int a;}",
                     "struct a_struct int a;",
                     "struct a_struct {int a;};"
                  ],
                  "answer":"struct a_struct {int a;};"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following accesses a variable in structure *b?",
                  "answers":[
                     "b->var;",
                     "b.var;",
                     "b(var)",
                     "var(b)"
                  ],
                  "answer":"b->var"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is structure called while coding?",
                  "answers":[
                     "str",
                     "structure",
                     "struct",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"struct"
               }
            ]
         },
         "hard":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the default return value of functions in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "int",
                     "void",
                     "char",
                     "string"
                  ],
                  "answer":"int"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What happens to a function defined inside a class without any complex operations (like looping, a large number of lines, etc)?",
                  "answers":[
                     "It becomes a virtual function of the class",
                     "It becomes a default calling function of the class",
                     "It becomes an inline function of the class",
                     "The program gives an error"
                  ],
                  "answer":"It becomes an inline function of the class"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is an inline function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "A function that is expanded at each call during execution",
                     "A function that is called during compile time",
                     "A function that is not checked for syntax errors",
                     "A function that is not checked for semantic analysis"
                  ],
                  "answer":"A function that is expanded at each call during execution"
               },
               {
                  "question": "An inline function is expanded during",
                  "answers":[
                     "compile-time",
                     "run-time",
                     "never expanded",
                     "end of the program"
                  ],
                  "answer":"compile-time"
               },
               {
                  "question":"When are the default values of a function defined?",
                  "answers":[
                     "When a function is defined",
                     "When a function is declared",
                     "When the scope of the function is over",
                     "When a function is called"
                  ],
                  "answer":"When a function is declared"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Where should default parameters appear in a function prototype?",
                  "answers":[
                     "To the rightmost side of the parameter list",
                     "To the leftmost side of the parameter list",
                     "Anywhere inside the parameter list",
                     "Middle of the parameter list"
                  ],
                  "answer":"To the rightmost side of the parameter list"
               },
               {
                  "question":"If an argument from the parameter list of a function is defined constant then",
                  "answers":[
                     "It can be modified inside the function",
                     "It cannot be modified inside the function",
                     "Error occurs",
                     "Segmentation fault"
                  ],
                  "answer":"It cannot be modified inside the function"
               }
            ]
         }
      },
      "arrs&strs":{
         "easy":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following refers to characteristics of an array?",
                  "answers":[
                     "An array is a set of similar data items",
                     "An array is a set of distinct data items",
                     "An array can hold different types of datatypes",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"An array is a set of similar data items"
               },
               {
                  "question":"If we stored five elements or data items in an array, what will be the index of the last data item?",
                  "answers":[
                     "3",
                     "4",
                     "5",
                     "88"
                  ],
                  "answer":"4"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax for declaring the array?",
                  "answers":[
                     "init array []",
                     "int array [5];",
                     "Array[5];",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"int array [5];"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax for printing the first element?",
                  "answers":[
                     "array[0]",
                     "array[1]",
                     "array",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"array[0]"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following gives the 4th element of the array?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Array[0];",
                     "Array(3);",
                     "Array[3];",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Array[3];"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which type of memory is used by an Array in C++ programming language?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Contiguous",
                     "None-contiguous",
                     "Both A and B",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Contiguous"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is an array of the one-dimensional arrays called?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Single Dimensional array",
                     "Multi-Dimensional array",
                     "2D Array (or 2-Dimensional array)",
                     "Both A and B"
                  ],
                  "answer": "2D Array (or 2-Dimensional array)"
                }
            ]
         },
         "medium":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"What is the correct definition of an array?",
                  "answers":[
                     "An array is a series of elements of the same type in contiguous memory locations",
                     "An array is a series of element",
                     "An array is a series of elements of the same type placed in non-contiguous memory locations",
                     "An array is an element of the different type"
                  ],
                  "answer":"An array is a series of elements of the same type in contiguous memory locations"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following gives the memory address of the first element in an array?",
                  "answers":[
                     "array[0];",
                     "array[1];",
                     "array();",
                     "array;"
                  ],
                  "answer":"array;"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which library is used to manipulate strings?",
                  "answers":[
                     "iostream",
                     "iomanip",
                     "string",
                     "container"
                  ],
                  "answer":"string"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the maximum number of parameters a string constructor takes?",
                  "answers":[
                     "1",
                     "2",
                     "3",
                     "4"
                  ],
                  "answer":"3"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which constant member function does not modify a string?",
                  "answers":[
                     "bool empty()",
                     "assign",
                     "append",
                     "delete"
                  ],
                  "answer":"bool empty()"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the difference between unsigned int length() and unsigned int size()?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Both can return a different value",
                     "They are same",
                     "Both return the length",
                     "None of the above"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Both can return a different value"
               },
               {
                  "question":"How many parameters can a resize method take?",
                  "answers":[
                     "1",
                     "2",
                     "1 or 2",
                     "3"
                  ],
                  "answer":"1 or 2"
               }
            ]
         },
         "hard":{
            "questions":[
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is correct about remove_extent() function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Removes the given dimension from an array",
                     "Removes the first dimension from the right of the array",
                     "Removes the first dimension from the left of the array",
                     "Removes the last dimension from the left of the array"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Removes the first dimension from the left of the array"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the header file is used for array type manipulation?",
                  "answers":[
                     "<array>",
                     "<type_traits>",
                     "<iostream>",
                     "std namespace"
                  ],
                  "answer":"<array>"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the use of is_array() function in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "To check if a variable is array type or not",
                     "To check if a variable is 1-D array type or not",
                     "To check if a variable is 2-D array type or not",
                     "To check if a variable is 1-D or 2-D array type or not"
                  ],
                  "answer":"To check if a variable is array type or not"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the use of is_same() function in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "To check if a variable is array type or not",
                     "To check whether two variables have the same characteristics",
                     "To check if two variable is of array type or not",
                     "To check whether two variables are different or not"
                  ],
                  "answer":"To check whether two variables have the same characteristics"
               },
               {
                  "question":"What is the use of rank() function in C++?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Returns size of each dimension",
                     "Returns how many total elements can be stored in an array",
                     "Returns how many elements are in array currently",
                     "Returns the dimension of an array"
                  ],
                  "answer":" Returns the dimension of an array"
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is correct about extent() function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Returns how many elements are in array currently",
                     "Returns the size of the 1st dimension",
                     "Returns how many total elements can be stored in an array",
                     "Returns the size of a given dimension"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Returns the size of a given dimension "
               },
               {
                  "question":"Which of the following is correct about remove_all_extents() function?",
                  "answers":[
                     "Removes the all dimension from an array",
                     "Removes the first dimension from the left of the array",
                     "Removes the last dimension from the left of the array",
                     "Removes the first dimension from the right of the array"
                  ],
                  "answer":"Removes the all dimension from an array"
               }
            ]
         }
      }
   }
]
